Le-Hi-Ho (The Lehigh Valley Homophile Organization), Bethlehem, PA Records GLBTQ.2012.06
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
Le-Hi-Ho (The Lehigh Valley Homophile Organization), Bethlehem, PA Records
1960-2002
GLBTQ.2012.06
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
3.0 Linear feet
Le-Hi-Ho was established in 1969 in Pennsylvania to be a safe and supportive organization for the GLBTQ community. This collection includes the group’s documents in addition to other organizations by state, articles, essays, and advertisements dating from the early 1960’s to the late 2000’s.
The Lehigh Valley Homophile Organization.
Biographical/Historical note
LE-HI-HO was organized in 1969 in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania to give homosexuals a safe place to meet, gain information, and dispel myths about homosexuality. The group provided counsel, legal aid, outreach programs, and education (from its own extensive library) to homosexuals as well as participating in political activism and sponsering social events. All information was conveyed through meetings and a monthly newsletter. They met for 14 years at the same place, The Unitarian Church of the Lehigh Valley, a church that fully supported and promoted their cause. After the founding of a community center in 1984, the Lamba Center in Allentown, meetings were held there.
Ronald Seeds, a Connecticut gay activist, helped in the original organization of this group and served as Director for a short time. Once a part of the Mattachine Society in New York, he expressed interest in starting a homophile organization in Pennsylvania in 1969. Leaving Pennsylvania with partner Rick for Newington, Connecticut in 1990, he became actively involved in PFLAG (Parents, Families, and Friends of Lesbians and Gays) and other organizations. He also assisted in the transfer of these records to Central Connecticut State University’s GLBTQ collection, donating many of his personal items as well.
Scope and Contents note
Documents relating to the growth of Le-Hi-Ho and its history are in this collection as well as information about other GLBTQ supportive groups in other states. Meeting agendas, minutes, correspondence, newspaper articles, event advertising, and financial paperwork from Le-Hi-Ho, and other homophile locations and institutions, are included. The collection also incorporates more broad information regarding GLBTQ topics such as aids, psychology, religion, and the arts ranging from the early 1960’s to 2002.
Seeds, Ronald; Christian gays; Gay rights -- United States -- History; Homosexuality -- Psychological aspects; Homosexuality -- United States; Homosexuality -- United States -- Newspapers; Homosexuality in the Bible; Lehigh Valley Homophile Organization; Same-sex marriage.
- Central Connecticut State University- Frank Gagliardi/ Ronald Seeds correspondence regarding donation of the collection, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- LE-HI-HO- By-laws committee- Drafts from first meetings, 1965- (Box 1, Folder 2)
- LE-HI-HO- By-laws, 1975, Proposed budget, 1976., 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- LE-HI-HO- History, 1969; 1970; 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- LE-HI-HO- Flyers, application forms, meeting schedule and events, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- LE-HI-HO- Articles, press releases, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- LE-HI-HO- Gay rights legislation (Pennsylvania), correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- LE-HI-HO- Board of Directors Meeting minutes, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- LE-HI-HO- Meeting minutes, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- LE-HI-HO- News “paste ups”, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- LE-HI-HO- Platform information for G.T. Watkins (President), Frederick Reed (Vice-President), F. Allen Ravert (Board), and Warren F. Ritter (Treasurer) of LE-HI-HO elections, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- LE-HI-HO- Treasurer’s Report, Saving Bank forms, 1969-1975; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- LE-HI-HO- “A Bibliography of books most of which deal with homosexuality, with four supplements”, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- LE-HI-HO- Library checkout forms, newsletter renewal forms. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- “Closets are for Clothes Only” Advertisement (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lehigh University- Brown and White Newspaper, September 15, 1972. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Lehigh University- Gay discrimination, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lehigh University- Student Homophile Group, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- “The Homosexual Student on Campus: A Bill of Rights.” (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Lehigh Valley Bail Fund- Brochure, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Lehigh Valley Gay & Lesbian Community Center- Flyers, events, newsletter, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Lehigh Valley News- Articles, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Ronald Seeds- Name Badge (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Ronald Seeds- Correspondence, 1969-1975; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Ronald Seeds- Correspondence, 1993; 1999-2001; 2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Ronald Seeds- Lambda Center Award (framed), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Allentown City Council on Gay Rights Issues- Community Report, correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Allentown Human Relations Commission- Meeting Minutes, Information, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "Allentown police cracking down on lewdness in park..." The Morning Call, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Edinger-Wyckoff Inc.- Blue prints for Community Center, 1980’s. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- “Real Life Guide”- Articles about Homosexuals, 1961-1963; 1975. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1961-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- GLBTQ related articles, 1980-1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- GLBTQ related articles, 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- GLBTQ related articles, No dates. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Le-Hi-Ho Buttons- From different events: "Christopher Street Liberation Day" & "Love is Gay Pride '75", various slogans "Gay is Good" & "Out Front"- 20 compartments inside box. (Box 1, Object 1)
- Homophile Action League, Philadelphia (H.A.L.)- Gay mini forum, Nov. 1972, Feb., 1973 [flyers] (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Homophile Action League, Philadelphia (H.A.L.)- Barbara Gittings- Correspondence, speech before the State Democratic Platform Committee, newspaper article., 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Homophiles of Penn State (HOPS) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lesbian and Gay Community Center, Bethlehem, PA, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lehigh-Pocono Committee of Concern (LEPOCO)- Bethlehem, PA- Newsletters, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Franklin Kamery... To Speak in Lehigh Valley, Le-Hi-Ho Press release, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Philadelphia- Philadelphia Gay Pride Committee event flyers, 1973; “Out Front” Philadelphia's first prime-time TV show flyer; Lesbian and Gay Task Force newsletters, 1987; “Killing Anthony” in Philadelphia, 1988; “Gay Philadelphia” in Today, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Pride '79, "Our Space For Growth" Conference flyer, Oct. 19-21, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Globe Times- Bethlehem, PA newspaper- Articles, 1969-1985; New Democratic Coalition, Bethlehem, PA- Flyers, newsletters, 1971, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Pennsylvania Rural Gay Caucus- By laws, 1976; Pennsylvania State Gay Convention, Pittsburgh- Flyer and Registration form, Oct. 27-29, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Community Advocate Newsletter for the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Lambda Legal Defense- Allentown, PA- Brochure, correspondence, events., 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- “Stonewall”- Newsletter Published for the Stonewall Bar, Allentown, PA (Box 2, Folder 13)
- “Amaranth” Spring 1993- Lehigh University; The Comenian, Moravian College- v. 65 no 20, May 19, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- American Foundation for AIDS Research- Newspaper article regarding the opening of an AIDS center in Bethlehem, PA, ribbon. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Women's Center, YMCA, Easton, PA- Feminist Forum, Flyers., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- The Pennsylvania Gay Conference- Program, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Pennsylvania- Office of the Attorney General Community Advocate Unit- Newsletter, 1974; Human Relations Act, 1975; Council of Sexual Minorities Legislative Committee- Legislative goals, 1976; Sexual Offenses Statute, n.d., 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Human Enlightenment- Trip notifications, correspondence., 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Homophile Union of Boston (HUB)- By-laws/ constitution, Newsletters, events, 1971-1972; Gay National Flower, 1975; Gay Community News, Boston, MA, 1987, 1971-1972; 1975; 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Student Homophile League of U. Mass. Gay Weekend poster, May 4-6, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- “Satellite”- Provincetown tourist guide., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Gay Activist Alliance of New Jersey- Letter., March 16, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Rutger’s University Student Homophile League- General event and group information 1970-1973; Conference of Gay Liberation- Speeches, announcements, program, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Gay Activist Alliance Gay Dance [flyer] 1973; Gay Activists Alliance, Hold Hands Across the George Washington Bridge, 1975 [flyers]; Gay Activists Alliance New York, flyer offering a list of gay organizations, 1970s?, 1972, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- National Gay Task Force (NGTF)- “Gay Civil Rights Support Statements and Resolutions Packet”, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- NGTF- Membership requests, fundraising, correspondence., 1985-1987; 1990. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Various New York flyers for places and events (Crimson Wreath, Brooklyn & Company, New York); Gayyellow Pages (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Roberts, Pudgy- Flyers for Female Impersonators, Transvestites., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Lesbian Center- New York; Lesbian Conference, May 18-20, 1973? Richmond College, NY [flyer] (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Homosexual Community Counseling Center, New York- Correspondence, conference material, articles, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Lavender Opinion, Ithaca, NY- Proposal for a Gay Press International newspaper, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Gay Student’s Caucus at Columbia University, New York, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Student Homophile League of Cornell University- Correspondence, flyers., 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Mattachine Society, NY- By-laws (1968), flyers, reports, correspondence., 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Mattachine Society, Washington- Constitution, By-laws, Policies., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Gay Activists Alliance of Washington, D.C.- Press release regarding police entrapment, 1972; Democratic platform on gay rights. (Box 2, Folder 37)
- National Gay Mobilizing Committee- Planning March on Washington postmarked., October 15, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- National Gay Student Center, Washington, D.C.- Letters., 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Chicago Gay Alliance- Constitution, membership information, Gay Pride Week fliers., June 22-July 1, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Mandrake Society of Greater St. Louis- Press release., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Kent Gay Liberation Front, Ohio- Plan for National Gay Conference., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Greater Cincinnati Gay Society- Correspondence, flyers, court case documents., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Ann Arbor Gay Community Spring Conference- Press release, announcement letter., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Triangle Gay Alliance (TGA), Raleigh, NC- Correspondence., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- GEMS organization- By-laws, meeting minutes, event advertisements, correspondence, Hartford/Manchester, CT., 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Gunnison, Foster Jr.- Institute of Social Ethics, Hartford, CT- Correspondence, newsletters, 1969-1971; newspaper articles, 1999., 1969-1971; 1999 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Gay/Lesbian History Stamp Club, Hartford, CT- Article, membership form., 1992 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Civil Rights (CCLGBTCR)- Newsletters, events, lobbying information, legislation, newspaper articles., 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- CCLGBTCR - OUT Awards- Program, forms, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Conn-Bi-Nation, Hartford, CT- Articles., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- The Pro-Family Coalition of Connecticut- “The Case for Same- Sex Marriage in Connecticut” (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Same Sex Marriage Debate in Connecticut, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Connecticut GLBTQ events put on by Love Makes a Family, Stonewall Congress, and Children from the Shadows, True Colors, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- University of Connecticut- Rainbow Center flyers., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee (CSLDC), Hartford, CT-Bulletins, correspondence, press releases, 1970-1971; Christopher Street West newsletter, Los Angeles, CA; Questionnaire for Washington D.C. (Box 2, Folder 56)
- “Gay Survival Kit”- Broadside printed on both sides & Emmaus Gay Switchboard and Drop-In Center- Flyer, San Francisco, CA. (Box 2, Folder 57)
- H.E.L.P. Los Angeles, CA- Flyer, correspondence., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Gay Community Services Center, Los Angeles- Correspondence, press release, flyers, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Homosexual Information Center, Los Angeles- Information about Center, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Homosexual Information Center, Hollywood- Correspondence, brochures., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Orcas Human Growth Center care of Stonewall Treatment Center, Orcas, Washington- Flyer for workshops., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Montrose Gaze Community Center, Houston, TX- General information., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- London/Amsterdam, Blueboy LifeStyle Travel- Brochure., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Gay Alliance for Equality, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada -Newsletter, November., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- ONE Inc., Los Angeles, CA- European Homophile Organization Tour, 1970-1971; newsletter, fundraising, membership, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Travel Motivators- Flyers for Gay vacations., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- “List of Gay Groups and Individuals”- List assembled in Minneapolis (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Eastern Regional Conference of Homophile Organizations- Correspondence., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Marches on Washington- Apr. 25, 1993 & Millennium March, 2000., 1993; 2000 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- National Coming Out Day cards. (Box 2, Folder 71)
- North American Conference of Homophile Organizations (NACHO)- Bulletins & Newsletters., 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- NACHO - Unity Questionnaire #4., July 7, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- NACHO- Clearing House Committee correspondence., 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- NACHO- Committee on Credentials reports, correspondence., 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Parents, Families, and Friends of Lesbians and Gays (PFLAG)-“Is Homosexuality a Sin?”, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- PFLAG- Resource listings, tips and general information, publications catalogs (Box 2, Folder 77)
- PFLAG- Articles, Alerts, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- PFLAG- Bisexual resources packet., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- PFLAG Connecticut - History (national and local)., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- PFLAG CT - Speech by Becky Glezen, First Church of Christ Congregational, Glastonbury; local news articles, newsletters, events., 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- PFLAG CT – Straight Spouse Network information and brochure. (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Various GLBTQ events nationwide- Flyers, posters, brochures. (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Heterosexual/Homosexual Rating Scale- From Sexual Behavior in the Human Male by Alfred C. Kinsey, Wardell B. Pomeroy, and Clyde E. Martin., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Dr. Ralph Blair, New York City Community College, Homosexual Community Counseling Center- Correspondence regarding male homosexuality survey conducted for doctoral study., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Northampton County Area Community College- Homosexual Community Study in Lehigh Valley Survey., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Gay Male Questionnaire Sexuality Survey- Karla Jay and Allen Young (authors), 1977; Gay Fantasies and Types survey by Greg Lehne (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Symposium on Human Sexuality, Allentown, PA- Symposium materials, program, 1974; National Institute for Applied Behavorial Science Basic Human Interaction Workshop for Homosexually Oriented Persons- Flyer and information, Mar. 23-25, 1973, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Homosexuality Questions and Answers- Reprinted by Le-Hi-Ho; “Answering Your Questions About Sexual Orientation and Homosexuality” by the American Psychological Association; Gay Speakers Bureau of Philadelphia, "Homosexuality, 25 questions and answers," brochure, 1970? (Box 3, Folder 6)
- “Gay Relationship” Gay Community Pamphlets, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- National Technical Assistance Center for State mental Health Planning Cultural Diversity Series “Meeting the Mental Health Needs of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Persons,” 1999. Prepared by Susan R. McCarn, N.C.C. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Gay Youth National Committee- Letter, 1973; “Just the Facts about Sexual Orientation & Youth”; Project Know flyer (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Homosexuality Speech- Transcript (no date or author) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Hockin, Robert. Dynamics of Homosexuality, College paper, April 28th 1971 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- “Homosexuals and the German Holocaust: A Selected Bibliography”, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- GLBTQ Book lists and Bibliographies; Book Review by Dr. C.A. Tripp of Sexual Inversion: The Multiple Roots of Homosexuality by Judd Marmor. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- “Homosexuals and U.S. Military Policy: Current Issues,” Congressional Research Service Report for Congress., 2005 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- “Homosexuals in America…” Gallup Opinion Index, No. 147., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Matthew Shepard Online Resources, “Nazi Anti-Jewish Speech vs. Religious Right Anti-Gay Speech”, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Lotus & Ron Seeds correspondence regarding decision to grant employee benefits to same sex partners., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Newsweek- Loud Family, p.48-49, March 12, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Mediated Solutions “The Living Together Worksheet” By Barry Simon., 2001 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Kurdek, Lawrence “Relationship Quality Study”, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Kincaid, Martha- Letter to the Editor, Cedar Crest Student Newspaper, Spring, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Kane, David- Plea for funding of a proposed center in Milwaukee, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- “Experts Seek Help for Homosexuals.” By Dr. L.B. Merrick, Psychologist; “Homosexuals Can be Cured” (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Advocates for Abused and Battered Lesbians (AABL)- Information., 1999 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Metroline- “The Intersex Community” by Kristan Higgins, “Teaching Intersex Issues” description, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- “In The Life” TV program- Flyers, correspondence, schedules, newsletters, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- ACLU Legislative Alert - Opposing Senate Bill, 83 to prohibit homosexuals from hired for certain positions; “Homosexual job-bias order worries police, jail guards”, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Cohen, Michael, Sexuality and Relationships Study, 1999- Survey, “Sex” by Thomas Moore, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Creed, Freddie, Account of the arrest of two lesbians, Birmingham, Alabama, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Taking Up Needles and Thread to Honor the Dead (article about AIDS Quilt)- Reprinted from "People," Oct. 12, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- The Draft and Homosexual deferment- How to organize draft resistance efforts, correspondence, articles, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- “VD Handbook, 1972?”; “Plain Talk about Venereal Disease,” 1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous articles, documents regarding GLBTQ issues. (Box 3, Folder 33)
- "Homosexuality and Christian Faith" by Theodore W. Jennings, Christian Century, February 16, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Christianity & Crisis- “A Special Issue on Homosexuality,”Vol. 37, Nos. 9 & 10, May 30 & June 13, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Kutztown Ministerial Association- Homosexuality and the Christian Responsibility- Study session notes., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- "The Bible and Homosexuality" by Rev. Richard Druckenbrod, July 19, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Catholic Parents Network- Retreat dates and information., 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Ex Gays Testimony- Flyers. (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Council on Religion and the Homosexual, San Francisco, Symposium on the Lifestyles of the Homosexual. Nov. 10-12, 1972; Nov., 9-11, 1973- Flyers. (Box 3, Folder 40)
- National Sex Forum, San Francisco- Course brochures., 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Presbyterian Gay Caucus- “Presbyterians for Gay Concerns.”, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Pittenger, Norman, "A Theological Approach to Understanding Homosexuality," Religion in Life, Winter., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Ringer, Francis E., "Toward Responsible Human Sexuality"- Speech, October, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Keff, Christine, “Proposed Pronouncement on Civil Liberties Without Discrimination…” United Church of Christ General Synod., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- North American Conference of Homophile Organizations, Religious Committee- Conference on Religion and the Homosexual, New York, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Rev. Leanne Tigert “The Spirit Enabled Them to Speak” Sermon- Worchester, MA, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Rizo, Chris, “Prop 22 Leads to Gay Mormon’s Suicide.”- California Triangle., 2000 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- “Unitarians on Homosexuality”; Unitarian Church of Lehigh Valley flyers., 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- American Orthodox Church, Scranton, PA- Homophile Apostolate (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Greater Bethlehem Area Council of Churches- Correspondence with Ron Seeds, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Metropolitan Community Church of Lehigh Valley- The Valley Star, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Breton, Rev. J.E. Paul - Printed newsletters, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Immanuel Congregational Church, Hartford, CT- “What’s the Story?” Sermon by Reverend Dr. Edward G. Horstmann., 2000 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- “Welcoming Congregations of New Haven, CT” n.d. (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Metropolitan Community Church, Washington D.C.- Flyers and information, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- United Church of Christ, "Jesus Christ Frees and Unites, Human Sexuality and the Needs of Gay and Bisexual Persons," Pamphlet, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Parents and Homosexuality, Conference, Jan. 22, 1973 [flyer] (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Bryant, Anita- Form letter, July, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- New Line Cinema Catalog, 1974; Filmmaker John Waters “Pink Flamingos”- Review article, movie poster, 1974; Andy Warhol ‘Women in Revolt”- Review article, movie poster, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Multi Media Resource Center, San Francisco, CA- Catalogs., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Invisible Minority: The Homosexual in Our Society, press releases, etc. about this filmstrip, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Christopher Larkin’s film “A Very Natural Thing” movie stills and review article., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Ruso, Vito A. "The Jail" announcement for film (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Several playbills, programs, and pamphlets from various GLBTQ related concerts, plays, and performances in Connecticut, Pennsylvania, and New York. (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Playboy Forum Reprints, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Publisher's announcements of new books, journals, movies, etc., 1972-2002 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Trust, Edmund, Gay Love... It Exists!- Flyer advertising program (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Young, Valerie “Towards an Increased Understanding of Whiteness in Relation to ‘White Racism'", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 69)